Hello everyone, you all are very welcome.
You're watching You the Real.  I am
your personal advisor Amit Raj Sharma.
If you all want to know about ICICI Poverty Life's I
Protect Super Plan
then check the description of the video.
You will
find a link to the plan video in the video description.
Thank you for your comment sir.
As you all know that
every day every video on the channel
comes according to your questions, suggestions and comments.
So stay connected to the channel.  Like and
share the video.  Subscribe to the channel and
turn on all the notification bells so
that you get all the latest videos and updates at the
right time.  So let us know
about the I Protect Smart Plus Plan of ICICI Pt. Life Insurance Company Limited.  Simply put, this is
a term insurance plan which has three
variants.  The first option is Life
Option, the second is Life Plus and the third is
Life Rebalancing.
You will choose one option from these three options.  The premium will be
paid to the company.  On that basis you will be
given life insurance here.  In this plan,
you get to see terminal illness cover in all the options.
You can assume the amount of cover for terminal illness to be equivalent to your time
because it is paid in the condition
when you are suffering from a condition
which may result in death within the next 6 months
and this has been said by not one but two medical
practitioners on the basis of the diagnosis
report i.e. two doctors.
So you will get the time already added
and the policy will terminate.  So first of all
we will learn about the Pay Life option here, in
which the first premium payment
term option is single premium i.e. paying
one time, in which
you will get a positive term of minimum 5 years and maximum 20 years
and the age limit for taking
this option has been kept from 18 to 65 years. If
you take the option of regular premium payment term, then you will pay premium for the number of years
of positive term.
In this also you
can take a positive term of minimum 5 years. You have two
options here for maximum, first is to
subtract your age from 85, that is, you
can remain under the cover till 85 years. Second
is whole life, in which you will subtract your age from 99 and the
policy term will be calculated.   The
age limit is 18 to 65 years.  In Limited Pay,
if the premium payment term is taken for 5 years, 7 years or 15 years, then the
minimum policy term will be
10 years.  You will be able to remain under cover till the maximum age of 85 years.
If you
take a premium payment term of 10 years, then the minimum
policy term will be 10 years or you will be
able to remain under the cover till the age of 85 years or
you will also be able to take the whole life option in it.  The age
limit is 18 to 65 years only.  If you take the
option of paying premium till the age of 60 years
under the limited premium payment,
then you will remain covered till the maximum age of 85 years
and the age limit for taking this option will be
18 to 55 years.  The premium
will depend on your age, gender, health,
policy term, premium, payment, term, and the
amount you are taking.  Now
this is a term plan and the first option of the term plan is
life option.  So it is absolutely simple.
Like in term plan,
benefits are available in case of death.  The policy does
not continue.  It gets terminated.  It will be like that.
If you have opted for regular pay or
limited pay, you will
withdraw seven times the annual premium.  Then we will
compare it and take out 105% of the base premium paid till the date of death.
Then
we will compare it with some assured on death.  That is, the sum assured
you have chosen while taking the plan.
Whichever is higher among the three will be the death benefit.  The
nominee will get it.  The policy will be closed.
However, the sum acquired amount itself is
higher.  You guys know this thing.
You also pay premium for the same.
In case of single premium, the
condition is that one and a quarter times the single premium
or the sum earned which is
called sum on death here will be given
and after that the policy will be closed.
You can choose different death benefit payout options in this option.
Which are four,
about which I will tell further.  So do
n't skip the video.
Watch it completely comfortably.  Suppose the person is a gentleman whose age is 35
years.  He took ICICI Pro Life's
iProtect Smart Plus option along with option
number one which is Life.  In this, a
policy term of 30 years was taken.
Took a premium payment term of 10 years.
He took a summer shot for ₹1 crore.  So in such a situation,
he will pay a premium of ₹44,350 annually.  That is,
if Mr. A dies during the policy term, the
nominee will
get the life cover amount of ₹1 crore and the
policy will be closed.  Even if he does
not die in the policy and if he gets a
terminal illness later on, in that condition the
nominee will not get the benefit, but this person will get it.
Mr. A, because he will be alive, will get the
claim of ₹1 crore
and the policy will be closed. Okay, let's
talk about the second option, that is Life Plus.
If you take the Life Plus variant, then the
conditions are the same in the case of single premium.
Minimum policy term of 5 years, maximum of 20 years,
age limit of 18 to 65 years. In the case of regular pay,
you will have the option to
take a minimum policy term of 5 years.  You
can remain under the cover till the maximum age of 85 years.  The age
limit is 18 to 65 years.
In case of limited pay, you can take a policy term of 5 years, 7 years, 10 years, 15 years
with a premium payment term of minimum
10 years.   You
can remain under the cover till the maximum age of 85 years.  And the age limit to avail this
option with limited premium payment term is
18 to 65 years.  ok sir.
And even if you choose to pay premiums till the age of 60,
you
can remain under cover till the maximum age of 85 years.
But the entry age limit will be 18 to 55 years.
Now what is the plus in this?  Like
in the life option, there was death benefit and
terminality.  Along with that,
accidental death benefit is also available in it.   The
accident is covered only if it occurs within 180 days from the date of accident.
As mentioned in the policy brochure, the name is
Priya ji, who is 32 years old.
He took the I Protect Smart Plus plan of ICICI Pt. Life Insurance
Company Limited
with variant number two
which is Life Plus.  He has taken a deal worth ₹1 crore.
So her
accidental death benefit cover of ₹1 crore will also be there
and she is taking the option of regular premium payment term
for 30 years.  That means
she will pay the premium for 30 years.  Will remain
under cover for 30 years.  So, in this case,
she will pay a premium of ₹16,679 every year
and will have a life cover of ₹2 crore for the entire 30 years.
Normal death costs Rs 1 crore and
accidental death costs plus Rs 1 crore.  Suppose
he dies after the completion of the 14th year of the policy, then the
policyholder will get ₹2 crore.  If the
death is accidental then only Rs 1 crore will be received, if it is a normal death then only Rs
1 crore will be received.  Ok?
In case of non-accidental death and terminality,
they will get a claim of only Rs 1 crore
and the policy will be terminated further.   The
third option here is the rebalancing
variant.  The minimum policy term in the rebalancing variant is
15 years.
With single premium, you will be covered for a maximum period of 20 years for the age group of 18 to 45 years.
In case of regular pay, the minimum
positive term is 15 years.  You will be able to remain under cover till the maximum age of 85 years.  The
entry age limit is 18
to 45 years.  In case of limited pay,
if you have taken a premium payment term of 5 years, 7 years, 10 years, 15 years
or if you
prefer to pay premium till the age of 60 years, then
also you can remain under the cover for a minimum of 15 years
because the minimum positive
term is 15 years.  You will be able to remain under cover till the maximum age of 85 years.  The
entry age limit for
this option is also 18 to 45 years.
Now what is there in rebalancing is that there is death
benefit and there is accident death benefit.
But the accidental death benefit becomes
zero from the 11th year of the policy.   The
company has provided a chart to understand how the balance is being maintained here.
We understand.  Suppose if death occurs in the first year
and the sum assured you have chosen.
If there is a normal death then 25% of the sum assured will be
received.  In case of accidental death,
75% of the sum assured will be given in addition.
If death occurs in the second policy year,
32.50% of the sum assured will be
received.  The policy will be closed.  But in
case of accidental death, then along with this,
67% of the sum assured i.e. 67.50% will be given
additionally.  If death occurs normally in the third year
then 40% of the sum assured.
But in case of accidental death, an
additional 60% of the sum assured will be given.
So this is how it is explained here every year.
You can pause and read here.
And by the 10th year, if there is a normal
death, then 92.50% of the sum assured will be
received.  If there is an accidental death, then
in that case 7.5% and extra amount
is available here.  Since the 11th year, you have been seeing that the
chart shows that the sum on
death, that is, 100% of the sum you are choosing, will be
available here.  No matter how the death occurs, the
accidental death
amount becomes zero here.  0%age.
ok sir.  Now there are four death benefit payout
options.  The first is lump sum that the
deceased nominee gets the amount in one go.
The policy got terminated.  The second is the income
option in which the death benefit
amount will be received at 10% every year for 10 years.
If it is taken in monthly installments then the
death benefit amount will be
0.8333%.
For every month.  Right?  The third
option in this is lumpsum and income option.  If
you choose the Lumpsum Plus Income option here, then
while purchasing the plan, you decide
what percentage of the death benefit
amount should be given to the nominee at one go.
Right?  After choosing this, the nominee will continue to receive
0.833% of the remaining amount
every month
as an income benefit for the next 10 years.  The fourth option
here is increasing income.
What will happen in increasing income?  Yes,
if you wish, you will start getting death benefit in monthly installments.
Otherwise, you
get 10% of your death benefit annually which keeps
increasing at a simple interest rate of 10% every year and
by the end of the 10th year it will amount to
145% of the summed amount.  It will happen, that means it will
increase by this much.  Ok?  Simple, understood
?  In this plan you
also get the option of life stage protection.  That means,
if you get married in the middle of the plan and
you do not want to take a separate term plan,
then you can add up 50% of your sum assured in this plan itself.
On the birth or adoption of the first child, you will get a 25% increase in the sum
assured.  You will also be able to
increase your sum assured by 25% on the adoption or birth of the second child.
If you have taken a home loan,
you can increase the amount equivalent to 100% of your sum assured
and if you increase the cover amount, the
premium will also increase.
You also get smart exit benefit in the plan.  You
can withdraw the premium amount by discontinuing the policy.
But when?  When you have completed 25 years of the policy
and the last
5 years of the policy are not left.  Along with this, your age should be
60 years.  When you
want to avail the Smart Exit benefit.  That means you
want to get out of the policy by taking back the premium you paid.
Ok?  After that the condition is that the
policy should be continuously enforced.  It is
not that even if you stop the premium midway,
you will not be able to exit.  Along with this,
if you have changed the
mode of premium payment term during the plan,
then in such a case you will have to wait for 3 years.
After that you will be able to exit.
All conditions apply.  Smart
Exit.  You also get the option of premium brake.
If you feel that
you are not able to pay the premium for the next 12 months in the policy, then in
such a situation you
give a request for return to the insurance company in
which you get a breaking period of 12 months.
Right?  And the
deferred amount that becomes due during the break period, that is, the
amount of due premium, you
pay it after the completion of the premium break period.
Ok?  There is no extra charge
and during the
premium break period, which is
12 months, if there is death
or something happens during this period, the
nominee gets the entire claim amount.  The
company simply deducts the premium that is due.
Here also the condition is the same that the
policy should be enforced.  If you have
paid the premium in annual mode, then
you will have to mention it in the return 30 days before the due date.  If you are
paying the premium in monthly installments, then
you will have to inform the insurance company by
submitting an application in return 15 days before the due date.  And when you
apply for a premium break period,
you have to pay the premium continuously
until your
request is accepted by the company.  Ok?
Because
if you
stop paying the premium before the request for premium break period is accepted and the grace
period is over, then your policy may
lapse.  You should understand this thing.
Another good thing about the premium break option is
that you can use the premium break option
multiple times.  But there should be a gap of
at least 5 years after taking a premium break.
Right?  Like once
you take it, then you are stuck for 5 years.  Then
you can take it.  Like the example
given here.  Suppose you
take the premium break option in the sixth year of the policy,
then you will wait for 5 years.  Then the second time you
want to take the option of premium break i.e.
relaxation, you will want to
take it from the 12th year.  Ok?  And the premium
break option will
not be applicable in the last 3 years of the premium payment term.
You will have to take it before that.  So
these were the benefits of this plan which are
available in the policy brochure.  I told you.
You can read the policy brochure now.
Now it will be easier for you to understand it.  There will be no
confusion.  And yes, if it is a term plan
then do not hide anything while taking it and do not
take it without reading the policy document.
Thanks you all.  Take care of yourself
Please like and share the video.
Please do tell us in the comment section
which plan you want the next video to be about.  Please comment.
Everything is free.  Thanks you all.
You guys take care of yourselves and explain one thing to yourself.